Buy bike insurance online
Get bike insurance at a discount of 50% Zero
depreciation bike insurance policy is the
cheapest you will find with us Everyone is busy selling bike and two
wheeler insurance
but no one is telling
how to use this insurance policy, that is,
if a bike insurance claim comes, then
how to file it and how it will be
processed because the coverage of the policy
and the quality of your insurance company will be
known only at the time of claim when
you use their service
What does it take to buy a policy Once
you have entered all the details, then you have to either enter your
UPI PIN or
enter the OTP of your debit or credit card You will get the
policy of any insurance company in 2 minutes There is no
problem in this Every insurance company is
good while buying a policy
Where does the problem arise when we do
not know the correct process of making a bike insurance claim, then it can take
weeks or should I say even months to get the claim
So friends, in today's
video we will understand in detail
how to file a bike or two wheeler insurance claim
What is the complete process of making a claim while filing a bike insurance claim
Which documents do you need?
When do you have to call the insurance company about this claim? The main reasons for bike insurance
claim rejection?
What are the top reasons for claim rejection? We will also
know that and along with this, I will also tell you the
solution to every reason of rejection and
how to avoid it. From the
bike accident to the receipt of
your claim money in your account, we are going to understand this entire
process step by step.
So if you have a two-
wheeler or a bike, then today's video is
very important for you to watch and is going to be very beneficial for you. Let's
not delay
and quickly start the video.
Friends, any accident happens, be it with your
bike, someone else's bike, or any car. The
first thing we have to do is
handle any medical emergency.
Whether we are injured in an accident or the other person is injured, whether it is
my fault or the other person's, whether we will get the claim
or not, all these are secondary matters. First of all,
handle the medical emergency. If someone is
injured, give first aid to someone.
If needed, provide them. After that, all the
work will be done. There is no problem. So
friends, the first step in the claim process
is filing an FIR and claim
intimation. If a major
bike accident occurs in which any other party is also involved and
someone else is also harmed, then the
first thing we should do is file an FIR.
What will happen by filing an FIR? Whatever happened on the spot,
in whatever sequence, in
whatever situation, an FIR document is the legal record of each and every thing.
Any statement can change tomorrow. To
avoid this,
you must file an FIR in the nearest police station so
that when
you need to
take any information as a reference in the claim in the future, then FIR is
a legal document to prove it. So,
definitely register an FIR of this incident in the nearest police station.
After this, friends, the next step is claim
intimation. When the situation is under control and
everything is under your control, then
you should inform the insurance company about this accident and this
claim.  Why is it
important to intimate this? When the
company will provide your insurance compensation, it
becomes our responsibility to inform the
insurance company about this incident in a timely manner.
For claim intimation, you simply need to
call the insurance company's toll-free number,
which you can find within your policy document.
You can make this call from your phone, i.e.,
when the bike is with you,
or
you can also process the claim intimation from the workshop where you get your bike repaired.
After calling the toll-free number, you will be asked for some information.
What will that information be and
how to process the claim intimation, once you
understand it. When you call the toll-free number, the
insurance company's customer
care employee will ask you for your
bike's registration number or
policy number so they
can verify your policy document. After that,
you will need to provide the insurance company with all the information related to the accident, including
where it occurred, how it occurred, when it occurred, and the
region.  You will have to provide the driving license number of the person who was driving the bike at the time of the accident, i.e.,
who was the driver. Keep in
mind that you have to provide
only the driver's driving license here. Do not provide details of anyone else's
driving license here.
You have to provide the driving license details of the person who was actually driving the bike at the time of the accident at the
time of claim intimation. Apart from this,
whatever damage has happened to our bike in the accident, whether it has been caused to
any other property, any
other vehicle, any third
party has been damaged,
we have to provide all those details in this claim intimation and
finally we will be asked in which garage we will get this bike
repaired so that
their company or the surveyor of the insurance company can reach there, so
we have to provide those details here also. If our
garage or workshop has not been finalized yet, then
we can also say that our garage is
not finalized yet, the workshop is not finalized.
Whenever we will park our bike in any workshop or garage
for repair, at that
time we will call on this toll free number and
inform that our  This is the claim number,
this is the policy number and we are getting
our bike repaired in this garage, in this workshop.
You send the surveyor here.
Friends, the second step in the bike insurance claim process
is Appointment of Surveyor
and Loss Assessment. That is, once you
intimate your claim on the toll-free number,
you will receive
your claim number in a text message and along with it,
you will also get the name and contact number of the surveyor.
After this, you
can also talk to the surveyor personally about the time when he will come to the workshop to
assess your loss, that is, to
see how much damage has been done to the bike.
When he comes to the workshop
or the bike comes to you,
he will see what all damages are inside the bike. Along with
this, he will also
instruct the workshop to prepare
a rough estimate of repairing this bike, what
parts are damaged, what parts will be
replaced,
and along with this, he will
also survey the damaged bike. The survey done for both these things
and along with that  They will send this
repair estimate and both these documents
to the insurance company
for approval. If a repair claim has been received under this policy for this bike,
please give us approval. When the
approval comes from the insurance company, the surveyor will
tell the workshop that you can start your work.
This approval is called work start
approval. This is a very important
step. The workshop will also call you and inform you
that your claim has been approved and we are
starting the repair work of your bike. The
most important thing you have to do here is to
check and find out that
all the parts that were damaged in your bike have been approved. Many times it happens
that we tell them to start the work, there is no
problem, and when the
bike is finally ready, we go to collect it, only to
find out that the headlight claim was not
received or the claim for one tire was not received. When
we debate with them as to why they did not pay this claim, the
surveyor says that they should
tell you this at that time.  When I said
that these parts have been approved and
only these parts have been approved for your work to start,
so whenever your
bike repair work starts, do
check all the parts that have been damaged, whether
you have got approval for all of them
from the insurance company or not. The
third step is friends repairs and final
survey. Once the approval for work to start is
received from the surveyor, the workshop
starts repairing the bike
and when the bike is ready, they
make the final invoice for it, that is, they make the bill in
which it will be written which part has been
replaced, which part has been
repaired and how much expense will be
charged against it. Along with this, they will
also intimate the surveyor that he should
survey the ready bike. After that, the surveyor visits the
workshop and he sees whether all the
parts that were damaged earlier have been replaced
or not. He
also takes photos of the damaged parts and along with that, the
vehicle that is ready  Photos of that are also taken
to keep proof that the
work of this vehicle has been done in the insurance and
after this they send this survey and this invoice and
other documents to the insurance company to
release the payment. Now you will have to complete some
pending documents here also
because now your claim is finally being processed
for payment. So,
which documents are required
for filing any bike insurance claim? It is
important to understand these as well. The first document is the
claim form.
Friends, the same information is mentioned in the claim form
which you tell the insurance company in the claim intimation -
where did the accident happen,
how did it happen, who was driving, what are their
details, what are the owner's details, what is the
total repair estimator, whether the
invoice amount has been made, all those details are
filled in it. So first of all
you will have to submit the claim form,
after that you will have to give the original RC to the surveyor,
you will have to submit the insurance policy copy,
apart from this the owner's PAN  Card
Aadhar Card For KYC,
you will also have to provide the PAN card and Aadhar card of the bike owner.
After this, you will also have to submit the driving license of the
driver who was driving at the time of the accident.
Now, the driving
license that is being taken here has to be of the driver
only because it is
not being taken as identity proof. If you
give the owner's driving license,
because the driving license is
taken to verify whether the
driver who was driving the bike at the time of the accident
is a legally valid driver or not. Do
not change or switch anyone's license. Use the
license of the person who was actually driving the bike and
you have to tell his details during the entire claim process.
Apart from this, if any FIR has been registered, then
you will also have to submit a copy of the FIR here. The
estimate of repair which was
made in the beginning, the invoice of repair which is the
final bill, the actual bill made for this
repair, you will also have to submit that if
it is a non-cashless claim, that is, if
you have directly paid the bill, then the amount of that payment will be deducted.
You will also have to provide the receipt. Apart from this, the
discharge [ __ ]
is satisfactorily satisfied with it and the insurance company will
keep it as a proof and finally if
it is a non-cashless claim then
you will also have to provide a cancelled cheque in which the
payment of your claim will come. Now,
cashless and non-cashless is being mentioned here again and again, so
once we have understood the documents, let us
also understand what a cashless and non-cashless claim is. Now in both these
processes, whether it is cashless or non-
cashless, the claim process remains the same, the
only difference is that the final bill
amount, if it was a cashless claim, then
you will have to pay only the difference amount, the difference between the
actual bill and the
approved amount,
you will have to pay only that bill.
In case of a cashless claim, now suppose I had a
bike, I got it repaired and the total bill was
₹ 440000, the claim was approved for ₹ h, so
if this is the workshop where I got my
bike repaired  I have got the repair done from a cashless garage, it is a
cashless workshop, so I will have to
pay only ₹2000000000 upfront.
After that,
within two to three weeks of submitting all the documents, the insurance company will
send my claim amount of ₹8000 to my account directly.
In case of non-cashless insurance, the
customer has to settle the workshop bill directly. Therefore, you should
try to get
your bike repaired only in a cashless network garage.
Most of these showrooms are their
workshops. Now friends, here comes the
most important part of the video: what are the
top reasons for bike insurance claim rejection
and what are their solutions. Now
I will tell you the statements that
surveyors actually use while
rejecting a claim, along with its
solution, I will tell you how you can avoid it. The
first statement, the most common
statement that surveyors use
to reject a claim is that your
damage is old, that is, it is 3, 4, 6 months
old damage, whereas  Actually, that damage is
recent, so what should you do in this case?
Whenever an accident occurs,
you have to
keep proof of that loss in the form of photos or videos of the damage to the car or bike because
suppose you intimate the claim after three-four days, it takes
two-four days for the surveyor to
come. Now the metal of the two-weather is
not that strong, it is a
thin metal, there are
more chances of rust in it and if a little
rust is seen anywhere, then the survey will
directly say that it is rusted,
this is a six-month old accident, you are
claiming it late. If you
have photo and video proof, then no one will be able to
challenge it and you will
not need to prove your point
because you already have proof of that accident. The
second biggest reason for claim rejection is
when the surveyor says that this accident did
not happen here, it did not happen at this time because
we generally do it without any reason.  They also
change the time and location of the accident. What is the reason
brother, why do you have to show such a far away location?
Show the road near you.
What is the problem brother, why do you have to show the time of 12100 in the night? Show the
time of 10100 in the morning. Your insurance policy
is valid for 24 hours all over India.
Your coverage will be there in it. So do
not change the location and time details without any reason
because technological things have become so
advanced that they will find out in 5 minutes
what was your location at that time
and if there are differences in it, then
your claim can be rejected due to colour factors. The
third reason for claim rejection
is that the driver of the bike is not the one
you have mentioned in the claim form or
in the claim intimation, whose
driving license you have given. What happens is
my bike, my friend took it from me
saying that I am taking the bike, an
accident happens, he does not have a license, then
what will I do, put my license,
but the surveyor will find out in 5 minutes that my bike is not the one you have mentioned in the claim form or in the claim intimation.
What was the location at that time, who was driving the bike and if there is even a
slight difference in this, if the facts are even
slightly different, then
using that it is assumed that
your entire claim is fake, whereas your
accident is genuine but you have
submitted someone else's document, you have wrongly mentioned
who was driving the bike and
if this is caught, your claim is rejected, then
give the bike to those who have a valid driving license to drive and secondly, if the person
driving the bike has a license then
put only his license, do not change these things without any reason, do
not tamper with these things, the
fourth reason for claim rejection is
friends that out of all your damages, some of the
damages are old, which means you will
not get the full claim, only some parts of your
latest damage will be repaired,
now it is the rule of insurance that you
cannot club together many damages and make a claim, if you
file a claim, then the latest damage is the
latest damage that has happened to the vehicle,
what do we do that sometimes  If there is an accident in the vehicle and
some minor damage occurs, then we
think let it go and take care of it along with the bigger one.
But in doing so, a lot of damages and
scratches accumulate and when finally
a major accident occurs and we say get
these repaired as well, at that time the claim is
rejected. So what should you do?
If there is any such damage in your vehicle
which you think you will
claim in the insurance someday, then claim it at the time when the damage occurred. Do
not make the next claim until the
damage becomes old and the surveyor will
tell you as soon as he sees this that this damage is
not from this accident and hence he will
reject your claim. If
you have to make a claim, then claim it at that time itself. The
fifth reason is that the
no claim bonus is wrongly mentioned in your policy.
Now, you get a discount in the insurance policy.
If you do not make a claim for the entire year, then the
insurance company
gives you a no claim bonus, due to which your
premium becomes cheaper. Now, this is not like this, no matter how much  There is
a fixed rule to get no claim bonus. When one year
is completed without any claim, then no
claim bonus is given at 20, after that 25, then 35,
then 45, then 50. My eligibility as per the policy was fixed
at 25 and the online app
automatically waived the no claim bonus at 50.
My policy was becoming cheaper, why should I
check it? I made the payment and the policy was issued.
Whose fault is it? It is my fault.
I have to check the NCB. When my eligibility is fixed
at 25, I should edit it in the app
or on the online website that this should come at 25 and not 50. I should pay the
premium accordingly. It will
not make much difference. There will be a difference of 30, 40, 50
but the entire claim gets
stopped because the first job of the surveyor is to
verify your NCB i.e. no claim bonus from your previous company.
If any mistake is found in it, then because
they know that most of the policies are available, they will
stop your claim or
approve a partial claim from it.  That means they will
not accept the full claim but will deduct some money from it. So
you have to enter the NCB details correctly,
this is our responsibility. The sixth
reason for bike insurance claim
rejection is that there is a difference in the ownership details.
I bought an old bike and got
my name updated in the RC. The
name of the old owner was removed but the
insurance policy is in the name of the old owner.
I did not make any changes in it. The bike met with an
accident and when I went to claim, the
surveyor said, brother, these are two
different people. You are the bike owner
but the owner in the policy is someone else, so
you will not get coverage for it. So what should I do?
When you get your name updated in the RC,
you also have to raise a
request for the endorsement of ownership transfer in your bike
insurance policy. If
you have bought it from an agent, then tell them. If
I have bought it online, then tell them there.
You can also raise this request by calling the direct toll free number of the insurance company. The
cost is also not much. The
name change will be done within ₹5000000 and
your  When the details in the bike and insurance policy match, and the
ownership
details match, your claim wo
n't be a problem. So, friends,
you've understood the entire process of claiming bike insurance
step by step.
You've understood the documents, where to file the claim intimation, and where to file it.
I've also guided you on why bike insurance claims are rejected, the major reasons for them, and how to avoid claim rejection. You won't encounter so much information in this video,
because these are the
reasons insurance
companies use to reject claims.
Now that you have the policy, it's
crucial to have this information. If you feel this video
was informative and
created value for you, and you're
happy with my efforts,
you can like the video to show your love and support. You
can share it wherever necessary.
If anyone else needs it,
please send them the information. And if you have
n't subscribed to the channel yet, please do
subscribe.  I,
Harvinder Singh, now take your permission. I will get your permission
in the next video. Till then,
take care of yourself, stay happy and healthy.
Jai Hind.